Whiting, Indiana: Generational Memory 1991-1993 ohrc102
Center for Documentary Research and Practice
- Westerfield, Herschel; Westerfield, Beverly, July 26, 1991; 91-042; Berry, Chad; 44 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 90 minutes; index
  Herschel Westerfield, born on November 19, 1933, and his wife Beverly Westerfield, born on July 24, 1935, recall their respective childhoods, memories, and traditions rooted in rural Kentucky. They share their memories of the Great Depression and World War II, as well as life before electricity and indoor plumbing. In addition, they speak of the family and Christian values they have as the foundation of their life and family.
  Kentucky; alcohol; electricity; family values; Great Depression; indoor plumbing; Kentucky oil fields; local crime; urban changes; World War II; Whiting Southern Baptist Church
- Whiting, Jack D.; Whiting, Joyce E., March 5, 1992; 91-155; Bodnar, John; 61 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 92 minutes; index
  Jack D. Whiting, and his wife, Joyce E. Whiting, discuss their respective parents, ancestries, and childhoods in Whiting, Indiana. Mr. Whiting speaks of his year in the service during World War II and his years working for Standard Oil Company. Mrs. Whiting recalls being written about by Life magazine for her cheerleading innovations and the letters she received from American servicemen abroad during World War II because of the magazine coverage. The couple also discusses pollution and local politics in Whiting, as well as the layoffs that followed the 1955 fire at Standard Oil.
  Sun City, Arizona; Whiting, Indiana; 1955 Standard Oil fire; cheerleading; Fourth of July; layoffs; local politics; Pearl Harbor; pollution; rhythmnastics; vaudeville; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; World War II; John J. Wargo Agency; Life; NIPSCO; Standard Oil Company; Elliott, Ray; Wargo, John J.; Whiting, William
- Wickhorst, Doris, July 19, 1991; 91-136; Dabertin, David; 35 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 77 minutes; index
  Doris Wickhorst, born on August 20, 1918, describes her childhood and adult life in Whiting, Indiana, her German ancestry, and her employment history. She recalls her experiences and memories of the Great Depression and World War II, including war rations. In addition, she speaks of the 1955 Standard Oil fire.
  Gary, Indiana; 1955 Standard Oil fire; coal heating; Great Depression; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; war rations; World War II; Standard Oil Company
- Williamson, Edward, July 23, 1991; 91-137; Dabertin, David; 23 pages; 1 tape, 1 7/8 ips, 58 minutes; index
  Edward Williamson, born on July 28, 1962, discusses his childhood, the effects of his parents' divorce, and his life in Whiting, Indiana. He speaks of his employment history, beginning as a paper boy and ending as circulation manager for the Whiting News Company. In addition, he emphasizes the importance of education and comments on the changes in local employment over the years.
  divorce; local employment; local wealth; pollution; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; AMOCO; Hoosier Theater; Immaculate Conception Catholic School; Video Data Services of Northwest Indiana
- Williamson, Lorraine, May 16, 1991; 91-034; Berry, Chad; 53 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 105 minutes; index
  Lorraine Williamson, born on January 24, 1927, joined by her mother, Sophie Gresko, discusses her memories of her childhood in Whiting, Indiana, including her participation in the opening parade of the Chicago World's Fair in 1933. She recalls the Great Depression, and the Korean and Vietnam Wars, during which she was in the diplomatic foreign service in East Asia. In addition, she and her mother discuss their Czechoslovakian heritage and culture, as well as the importance of education.
  Czechoslovakia; Florida; Korea; 1933 Chicago World's Fair; apple strudel; Education; ethnic diversity; family values; Great Depression; Korean War; Vietnam War, 1961-1975; worker's compensation; Inland Steel; Kocan, Helen
- Wunder, Rudolf H., Sr., October 22, 1990; 91-001; Klemm, Verda; 23 pages; 2 tapes, 1 7/8 ips, 97 minutes; index
  Rudolf H. Wunder, Sr., born on June 27, 1910, discusses his emigration from Germany, his father's service in the German army during World War I, and his brother's service in the United States Army during World War II. He speaks of celebrities he waited on while working at the Windemere Hotel in the nineteen twenties, including Babe Ruth, and he recalls Prohibition and the Great Depression. In addition, he comments on his successful career as a hairdresser, cosmetologist, and businessman in Whiting, Indiana.
  hairdresser; Chicago, Illinois; Germany; 1919 Treaty of Versailles; celebrities; family values; inflation; unions; World War I; World War II; Windemere Hotel; Ruth, George Herman, Jr. "Babe"; Stagg, Alonzo